Clyde Beatty and Cole Bros. Circus posters 99.01.ClydeBeattyCircus
University Archives, Texas State University
Clyde Beatty and Cole Bros. Circus posters
circa 1964
University Archives, Texas State University https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu
Clyde Beatty-Cole Bros. Circus
99.01.ClydeBeattyCircus
1.75 Linear Feet One flat box (21 x 25).
Collection of posters advertising the Clyde Beatty and Cole Bros. Circus performances that took place in San Marcos, Texas on September 15th, probably in the year 1964.
Box 1
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Scope and Contents
Collection of posters advertising the Clyde Beatty and Cole Bros. Circus performances that took place in San Marcos, Texas on September 15th, probably in the year 1964. Twelve of the posters include text only. Posters with images consist of two parts: a larger poster containing the title and image and a second, smaller poster containing date and location information pasted to the bottom. Arranged according to subject.
Historical note
Clyde Beatty was a circus entertainer and lion tamer who ran his own circus. After facing financial harship in 1956 Beatty sold his circus to Frank McClosky and Walter Kernan. In 1959 the circus was renamed The Clyde Beatty Cole Bros. Circus. Clyde Beatty continued to perform with the show until his death in 1965.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Harold C. Tedford, former instructor, Theater Department, in October 2017.
Index Terms
Places
San Marcos (Tex.) -- History
- Horizontal Posters, 1964; Four 42" x 14" vertical posters, text only.
- Vertical Posters, 1964; Five 27.5" x 41.5" vertical posters, text only.
- Horizontal Posters, 1964; Three 28" x 21" horizontal posters, text only.
- Lion Tamer Poster, 1964; Two 27.57" x 29" posters with image of a lion tamer with his big cats.
- Seal Poster, 1964; 28" x 48.5" poster featuring seals.
- Clowns with Pig Poster, 1964; Two 36" x 40.75" posters, image includes clown trio with pig.
- Clowns Poster, 1964; One 36" x 41" poster; image includes clown quartet.
- Wild Animals Poster, 1964; Two 28.25" x 28" posters showing a variety of wild animals in a jungle setting.
- Monkey Musicians Poster, 1964; Two 21" x 36" posters with image of a quartet of monkey musicians.
- Bear Poster, 1964; One 48.5" x 28" poster with image of performing bears and a woman.
- Clowns with Dynamite Poster, 1964; Two 28" x 48" posters with image of three clowns and a stick of dynamite.
- Clowns with Dynamite, 1964; One 36" x 20.5" posters with image of three clowns and a stick of dynamite.
- Elephant & Butterfly Poster, 1964; One 49" x 14" poster with image of a female perfomer dressed as a butterfly riding an elephant.
- Trick Riders Poster, 1964; One 27.75" x 27.5" poster with image of male and female riders standing on two horses' backs with a clown on the left edge.
- Tight Rope & Hoop Poster, 1964; One 49" x 14" poster showing two female tight rope walkers and third with a hoop; a clown is in the lower right corner.
- Tight Rope Walkers, 1964; One 49" x 14" poster with image of three tight rope walkers and a clown.
- Wild Animals Poster, 1964; One 49" x 14" poster showing a variety of wild animals in a jungle setting.
- Majorette & Horses Poster, 1964; One 49" x 14" poster with image of a majorette on an elephant and a quartet of horses standing on their back legs in front of a trainer.
- Circus Poster, 1964; One 36" x 41" poster with image of a clown, two female trapeze artists, and one male trick rider with his horse.
- Clown Quartet Poster, 1964; One 28" x 28" poster show a group of four clowns.
- Clown Trio Poster, 1964; One 27.75" x 27.75" poster showing three clowns.